<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CMD on Hugo Grimoire</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/categories/cmd/</link><description>Recent content in CMD on Hugo Grimoire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trimad.github.io/categories/cmd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows Defender Firewall</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-03-03-windows-defender-firewall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-03-03-windows-defender-firewall/</guid><description>
Examples of rules are commonly used in network setups where specific programs or ports need to be allowed through the firewall to ensure that they can communicate with other devices or software.</description></item><item><title>OpenAI Whisper</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-02-24-openai-whisper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-02-24-openai-whisper/</guid><description>
Whisper is a general-purpose speech recognition model. It is trained on a large dataset of diverse audio and is also a multi-task model that can perform multilingual speech recognition as well as speech translation and language identification.
GitHub Repository Installation 1pip install git+https://github.com/openai/whisper.git Fix CUDA not detecting GPU Whisper will default to the CPU if a GPU is not detected, which is considerably slower. 1pip uninstall torch 2pip install torch torchvision torchaudio --extra-index-url https://download.</description></item><item><title>net user</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-02-22-net-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-02-22-net-user/</guid><description>
The "net user" command is a Command Prompt (CMD) command used to manage user accounts on a Windows operating system. It can be used to create, modify, or delete user accounts, as well as to change passwords and manage group memberships.</description></item><item><title>Uninstall Third-Party Drivers with CMD</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-02-06-uninstall-drivers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-02-06-uninstall-drivers/</guid><description>
You can uninstall third-party drivers (such as the WAVES MaxxAudio Pro driver) from the Command Prompt (CMD) by using the &amp;quot;pnputil.exe&amp;quot; utility. Here's the basic process:
Open Command Prompt as administrator: Press the Windows key + X, and then select &amp;quot;Command Prompt (Admin)&amp;quot;.
Type the following command and press Enter:
1pnputil.exe -e 2# or export the list to a file 3pnputil.exe &amp;gt; !drivers.csv This command lists all the third-party drivers installed on your system.</description></item><item><title>All About Time</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-02-02-all-about-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2023-02-02-all-about-time/</guid><description>
The first command, &amp;quot;wmic path Win32_OperatingSystem get LastBootUpTime&amp;quot;, is a Windows Management Instrumentation (WMI) command that retrieves the time the operating system was last booted. The second command, &amp;quot;systeminfo | find &amp;quot;System Boot Time&amp;quot;&amp;quot;, is a Windows Command Prompt command that uses the systeminfo command to retrieve system information, which is then piped (|) to the find command to search for the specific line containing &amp;quot;System Boot Time&amp;quot;. The third command, &amp;quot;(get-date) - (gcim Win32_OperatingSystem).</description></item><item><title>Download YouTube Videos</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2022-04-16-downloading-youtube-videos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2022-04-16-downloading-youtube-videos/</guid><description>
yt-dlp yt-dlp is a free and open-source command-line tool for downloading videos and audio from YouTube and other video hosting sites. It is a fork of youtube-dl with additional features and improvements, including better performance and more frequent updates. Unlike youtube-dl, which has faced various legal challenges and takedowns, yt-dlp is actively maintained and regularly updated to ensure compatibility with the latest changes in video hosting sites. GitHub Repository Download the Windows executable Download a YouTube video with default settings:</description></item><item><title>ffmpeg</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2022-01-27-ffmpeg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2022-01-27-ffmpeg/</guid><description>
ffmpeg is a complete, cross-platform solution to record, convert and stream audio and video.
ffmpeg Download ffmpeg Documentation Audio Processing Convert to 8kHz, single-channel PCM 1ffmpeg -i &amp;#34;input.mp3&amp;#34; -ar 8000 -ac 1 output.wav Convert to 16kHz, single-channel PCM 1ffmpeg -i &amp;#34;input.mp3&amp;#34; -ar 16000 -ac 1 output.wav Convert to 48kHz, single-channel PCM 1ffmpeg -i input.mp3 -ar 48000 -ac 1 output.wav Video Processing Add Music to a Video 1ffmpeg -i video.mp4 -i music.</description></item><item><title>Robo Mirror</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2019-02-28-robo-mirror/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2019-02-28-robo-mirror/</guid><description>
This batch file utilizes robocopy to mirror a list of files contained within &amp;quot;targets.txt&amp;quot; in the same directory.</description></item></channel></rss>