<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>processing on Hugo Grimoire</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/tags/processing/</link><description>Recent content in processing on Hugo Grimoire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trimad.github.io/tags/processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fridge Magnet Simulator</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2018-11-16-fridge-magnet-simulator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2018-11-16-fridge-magnet-simulator/</guid><description>
Launch this sketch is a new window (recommended)
Launch p5.js web editor
This is a virtual simulation of the magnets on my girlfriend's fridge.</description></item><item><title>Orbiting Pixels Utility</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2018-11-12-orbiting-pixels-utility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2018-11-12-orbiting-pixels-utility/</guid><description>
Launch this sketch is a new window (recommended)
Launch p5.js web editor
This is not a program that should be running in a browser. With that said, writing this program was a laborious process that taught me a lot about JavaScript, about Processing, and about optimization. The algorithm I implemented works first by creating a grid of evenly-spaced points. Each points has a corresponding object that rotates around that point that can be assigned characteristics such as rotation radius, a shape, and a color that corresponds to an x and y position on a source image.</description></item><item><title>Ulam Spiral</title><link>https://trimad.github.io/post/2018-05-17-ulam-sprial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trimad.github.io/post/2018-05-17-ulam-sprial/</guid><description>
Launch this sketch is a new window (recommended)
Launch p5.js web editor
The Ulam Spiral or prime spiral is a graphical depiction of the set of prime numbers, devised by mathematician Stanislaw Ulam in 1963 and popularized in Martin Gardner's Mathematical Games column in Scientific American a short time later. It is constructed by writing the positive integers in a square spiral and specially marking the prime numbers.
What I've done differently is allowed for iterating every integer in the grid forwards or backwards to search for long, connected diaganal lines of prime numbers in the grid.</description></item></channel></rss>